Register of the I. I. Serebrennikov papers
Hoover Institution Archives
I. I. Serebrennikov papers
1906-1969
51004
Hoover Institution Archives
29 manuscript boxes, 11 envelopes, 3 album boxes (14.2 linear feet)
Diaries, correspondence, writings, photographs, clippings, and notebooks relating to the Russian Civil War in Siberia, Russian émigrés in the Far East, and Chinese history and culture. Also available on microfilm (33 reels).
Serebrennikov, I. I. (Ivan Innokentʹevich), 1882-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1951.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Forms of Material Available
Also available on microfilm (33 reels).
Biographical Note
1882 July 26 Born, Znamenskii-Verkholenskii, Irkutsk, Siberia
1901-1902 Studied at Military Medical Academy, St.Petersburg
1907 Arrested in connection with Socialist Revolutionary organization
1913-1917 Municipal Secretary for town of Irkutsk
1915 Director for the Affairs of the East Siberian Section of the Imperial Russian Geographical Society Vice-Chairman of local Committee of the Union of Towns in Irkutsk Delegate from Irkutsk City Duma to All-Russian Food Congress Representative of Zemgor at Siberian Factories Conference
1917 Organized group of Siberian autonomists Member of Siberian (later All-Russian) Government at Omsk
1918 Minister of Supply for Siberian Government, acting chairman of Council of Ministers in absence of P. V. Vologodsky Head of Delegation of Siberian Government to State Conference of Ufa; Vice-Chairman of Conference
1919 Member of Institute to Study Siberia
1920 Immigrated to Harbin (Manchuria)
1937-1940 Author, Moi Vospominaniia (Memoirs)
1953? Died
Scope and Content Note
Diaries, correspondence, writings, photographs, clippings, and notebooks relating to the Russian Civil War in Siberia, Russian émigrés in the Far East, and Chinese history and culture. Also available on microfilm (33 reels).
Refugees.; Russians--China.; Russians--East Asia.; China--Civilization.; China--History.; Siberia (Russia)--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.
- Diaries, 1920-1956 (Boxes 1-4A)
  Scope and Contents note
  Diaries in bound notebooks containing diary entries, photographs, newspapers and magazine clippings, and handwritten drafts of poems and essays by Ivan I. and Alexandra N. Serebrennikov (wife of Ivan Innokentievich Serebrennikov), arranged chronologically.
  - 1920 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - 1920-1939 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - 1931-1932 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - 1932-1933 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - 1933-1934 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - 1934-1935 (Box-folder 1A: 1)
  - 1935-1936 (Box-folder 1A: 2)
  - 1936-1937 (Box-folder 1A: 3)
  - 1937-1938 (Box-folder 1A: 4)
  - 1938-1939 (Box-folder 1A: 5)
  - 1939-1940 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - 1940-1941 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - 1941-1942 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - 1943-1944 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - 1945 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - 1945-1946 (Box-folder 3: 2-3)
  - 1946 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - 1947-1948 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - 1948 (Box-folder 4: 2-3)
  - 1948-1949 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - 1949-1950 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - 1950-1951 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - 1954-1955 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - 1955 (Box-folder 4A: 1)
  - 1955-1956 (Box-folder 4A: 2)
- Correspondence, 1920-1946 (Boxes 4A-8)
  Correspondence of Alexandra N. and Ivan I. Serebrennikov, arranged alphabetically by last name of correspondent or name of organization.
  - Notebook of copies and drafts of letters sent in English, 1929 (Box-folder 4A: 3)
  - Notebooks containing lists of letters sent, 1927-1929, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 4A: 4)
  - General, 1932 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Unidentified, 1922-1941 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Alebrazantsev, Elena, 1941, 1946 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - Amende, Yakov F., 1936 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - American Express Co., Inc., 1937 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Antudevich, Z. I. and I. A., 1937-1939 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Arlington, L. C., 1936-1937 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Asia Magazine, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Bachenas, O. G., 1922-1928 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Baikov, N., 1941 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Bajenoff, N. P., 1937 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - Balashov, A., undated (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Banque Russo-Asiatique, Peking, 1925 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - Batourin, A. O., Mr. and Mrs., 1923 (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - Bauer, A., Mrs., 1936 (Box-folder 5: 15)
  - Berezovskii, Efim P., 1936-1941 (Box-folder 5: 16)
  - Bergman, G., Dr., 1922 (Box-folder 5: 17)
  - Briantsev, E., undated (Box-folder 5: 18)
  - British Municipal Council, Tientsin, 1935 (Box-folder 5: 19)
  - The Cathay (periodical), 1934 (Box-folder 5: 20)
  - Chamberlin, William Henry, 1936 (Box-folder 5: 21)
  - Chapman, M. W., 1935 (Box-folder 5: 22)
  - Chase Bank, Tientsin, 1932 (Box-folder 5: 23)
  - Chepensky, V., 1939 (Box-folder 5: 24)
  - Cherb'entsev, Gennady, 1922-1923 (Box-folder 5: 25)
  - Cherdynzeff, M. V., Dr., 1942 (Box-folder 5: 26)
  - Chertkoff, George I., 1931-1942 (Box-folder 5: 27)
  - Chetverikov, Ivan S., 1921-1922 (Box-folder 5: 28)
  - The China Journal (periodical), 1932-1940 (Box-folder 5: 29)
  - Damskii Kruzhok Dal'nevostochnavo Rossiiskavo Doma (Ladies' Circle of the Far Eastern Russian Home), 1937 (Box-folder 5: 30)
  - Didkovsky, M., 1931 (Box-folder 5: 31)
  - Dobrokhotov, Nikolai M., 1931 (Box-folder 5: 32)
  - Dom Miloserdiia vo Imia Prep. Serafima Sarovksavo (The Reverend Serafim Sarovskii Charity Home), 1932 (Box-folder 5: 33)
  - Egoroff, A. A. and K. F., 1922-1942 (Box-folder 5: 34)
  - Erwin, E. S. (Assistant Comptroller, Stanford University), 1932, 1934 (Box-folder 5: 35)
  - Filimonov, B. B., 1932-1944 (Box-folder 5: 36)
  - Fisher, H. H., Dr., 1930-1941 (Box-folder 5: 37)
  - Foreign Affairs (periodical), 1935 (Box-folder 5: 38)
  - Gantimuroff, N. P., Prince, 1938-1943 (Box-folder 5: 39)
  - Gantimuroff, V. I., Prince, 1938-1940 (Box-folder 5: 40)
  - Gaponovich, Ivan I., undated (Box-folder 5: 41)
  - Gavrilovich, I. M., 1920-1921 (Box-folder 5: 42)
  - Gelazsaev, B. (?), undated (Box-folder 5: 43)
  - Gerasimov, A., 1931-1932 (Box-folder 5: 44)
  - Glotov, S. Z., 1920 (Box-folder 5: 45)
  - Golovko-Ulazovskii, N. A., 1933-1935 (Box-folder 5: 46)
  - Golubev, A., 1929 (Box-folder 5: 47)
  - Goutchkoff, N. I., 1932-1933 (Box-folder 5: 48)
  - Grebentschikoff, George, 1927-1935 (Box-folder 5: 49)
  - Greene, G. A., Jr., 1933 (Box-folder 5: 50)
  - Grizoff, A. A., 1939-1941 (Box-folder 5: 51)
  - Guins, George C., Prof., 1932-1941 (Box-folder 5: 52)
  - Hayes, Newton, 1931 (Box-folder 5: 53)
  - Howland, Charles P., 1932 (Box-folder 5: 54)
  - Hunter, Dard, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 5: 55)
  - Il'kov, Alexei K., 1933 (Box-folder 5: 56)
  - Information and Service Bureau, 1937 (Box-folder 5: 57)
  - Innokentii, M., 1930 (Box-folder 5: 58)
  - Institut Iapono-Russkavo Obshchestva (Institute of the Russian-Japanese Society), 1922 (Box-folder 5: 59)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1933 (Box-folder 5: 60)
  - Ioseiarevskaia, I. N. (?), 1922-1924 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Isaev, Ivan, 1937 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Ivanoff, E., 1924 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Johansen, Dorothy O., 1935-1936 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Kanoo, Michimasa, 1943 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Karpusheva, M., 1924-1929 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Kharbin, V. F., 1924-1929 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Kharbinskoe Vremia, 1932-1934 (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - Khorvat, Dmitrii, L., 1929-1932 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - Klemm, Vasily O., 1936 (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - Kniaseff, N. N., 1941 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - Kohaut, Nikolai, Captain, 1920 (Box-folder 6: 12)
  - Kolchanoff, L. P., 1939-1940 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - Koloboff, A., 1924-1926 (Box-folder 6: 14)
  - Koloboff, M. V., 1933-1940 (Box-folder 6: 15)
  - Koulaieff, I. V., 1937-1938 (Box-folder 6: 16)
  - Kozlov, I., 1941-1942 (Box-folder 6: 17)
  - Koz'min, N. N., 1921-1926 (Box-folder 6: 18)
  - Kozoolin, M., Mrs., 1927 (Box-folder 6: 19)
  - Kroll, M. A., 1920-1939 (Box-folder 6: 20)
  - Kukuranoff, L., 1936-1941 (Box-folder 6: 21)
  - Kunis, Zelma M. and I. S., 1923 (Box-folder 6: 22)
  - Lavrentieff, K., 1943 (Box-folder 6: 23)
  - Liubimov, G., 1922-1943 (Box-folder 6: 24)
  - Lutchev, Yevgeny V., 1934 (Box-folder 6: 25)
  - Luzac and Co., 1935 (Box-folder 6: 26)
  - Maevsky, Z. N., 1924-1929 (Box-folder 6: 27)
  - Mantsvetov, Fedor S., 1932 (Box-folder 6: 28)
  - Margold, Stella K., Mrs., 1932, 1934 (Box-folder 6: 29)
  - Markovskii, T., 1920-1924 (Box-folder 6: 30)
  - Meetshoorin, A. P., 1923-1930 (Box-folder 6: 31)
  - Mehnert, Klaus, Dr., 1943 (Box-folder 6: 32)
  - Mertans, A., 1937 (Box-folder 6: 33)
  - Mikhailovskii, Boris M., 1920 (Box-folder 6: 34)
  - Molostvov, A., undated (Box-folder 6: 35)
  - More, E., 1933 (Box-folder 6: 36)
  - Mosivit, A. T., 1924-1928 (Box-folder 6: 37)
  - Nachal'nik Kantseliarii Glavy Russkoi Emigratsii Na Dal'nem Vostoke (Head of the Office of the Chief of Russian Emigration in the Far East), 1936 (Box-folder 6: 38)
  - National City Bank of New York, 1929-1933 (Box-folder 6: 39)
  - National Library of Peiping, 1933 (Box-folder 6: 40)
  - Natsional'noe Informatsionnoe Biuro, 1930 (Box-folder 6: 41)
  - Obshchestvennaia Deshevaia Stolovaia (Low-Priced Public Dining Room), undated (Box-folder 6: 42)
  - Obshchestvo Izucheniia Man'chzhurskavo Kraia (Society for the Study of Manchuria), 1929 (Box-folder 6: 43)
  - Obshchestvo Sibiriakov v Kharbine (Society of Siberians in Harbin), 1932-1933 (Box-folder 6: 44)
  - Okulitch, I. K., 1941 (Box-folder 6: 45)
  - Orlov, A., 1932-1940 (Box-folder 6: 46)
  - Ossipoff, N. I., 1924-1925 (Box-folder 6: 47)
  - Osterman, M. E., 1934-1940 (Box-folder 6: 48)
  - Ostrovsky, A., 1939 (Box-folder 6: 49)
  - Otoblina, K. S., undated (Box-folder 6: 50)
  - Parus (periodical), 1933-1934 (Box-folder 6: 51)
  - Pavlov, Sergei, 1923-1941 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Pavlovsky, M., 1938 (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - Pecheniik, A., 1925 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - Pedashenko, A., 1936 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - Pershin, Dmitrii P., 1929-1936 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Pervaia Rossiiskaia Gimnaziia v Tian'tszinie (First Tientsin Russian High School), 1940-1945 (Box-folder 7: 6)
    Includes correspondence from Rossiikaia gimnaziia v g. Dairenie.
  - Pervaia Russkaia Tian'tszinskaia Smieshannaia Progimnaziia (First Russian Co-educational School in Tientsin), 1932-1938 (Box-folder 7: 7)
    Includes invitation from Tientsin Grammar School.
  - Petrov, N. F., 1935 (Box-folder 7: 8)
  - Petrov, V. N., 1922-1934 (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - Phoenix Publishing Co., 1935 (Box-folder 7: 10)
  - Pochekunin, I. I., 1938 (Box-folder 7: 11)
  - Popoff, G., 1936 (Box-folder 7: 12)
  - Popov, K., 1941 (Box-folder 7: 13)
  - Popuov, N. I., 1924 (Box-folder 7: 14)
  - Pravlenie Zarubezhnoi Stanitsy Irkutskavo Kazach'iavo Voiska (Directorate for the Foreign Village of Irkutsk Cossack Troops), 1934 (Box-folder 7: 15)
  - Prishchepenko, I. D., 1937-1939 (Box-folder 7: 16)
  - Purin, A., 1932-1943 (Box-folder 7: 17)
  - Raichbaum, D. Y., 1934 (Box-folder 7: 18)
  - Remer, C. F., Prof., 1932, 1935 (Box-folder 7: 19)
  - Rerikh, N. K., 1934-1935 (Box-folder 7: 20)
  - Robb, Varvara, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 7: 21)
  - Romanov, F., 1936-1937 (Box-folder 7: 22)
  - Rozanov, Vasily I., 1933-1941 (Box-folder 7: 23)
  - Russkii Natsional'nyi Klub (Russian National Club), 1928-1937 (Box-folder 7: 24)
  - Russkii Zagranichnyi Istoricheskii Arkhiv v Prage (Russian Historical Archives Abroad--in Prague), 1928-1939 (Box-folder 7: 25)
  - Rybalko, N. P., 1936-1940 (Box-folder 7: 26)
  - Safonoff, P., 1931-1934 (Box-folder 7: 27)
  - Sander, Chr., 1922-1923 (Box-folder 7: 28)
  - Sapelkin, V. V., 1941 (Box-folder 7: 29)
  - Savin, E., 1943-1945 (Box-folder 7: 30)
  - Savintseff, Peter, 1939 (Box-folder 7: 31)
  - Semenoff, Alexis A., 1927-1930 (Box-folder 7: 32)
  - Semenov, Grigorii M., 1936 (Box-folder 7: 33)
  - Serebrennikov, Alexandra N., (letters from Ivan I. to Alexandra N. Serebrennikov), 1932-1937 (Box-folder 7: 34)
  - Serebrennikov, G. S., 1939-1940 (Box-folder 7: 35)
  - Serebrennikov, Ivan I., (letters from Alexandra N. to Ivan I. Serebrennikov), 1931-1937 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Shanghai Zaria(periodical), 1929 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - Shirokogoroff, E., Prof., 1940-1942 (Box-folder 8: 3)
  - Shronin, G., 1937 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - Sibirskii Dom (Siberian Home), 1935 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - Silinskaia, K. Y., 1923 (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - Simon, Archbishop, 1932 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - Slovo Printing and Publishing Co., 1936 (Box-folder 8: 8)
  - Smirnoff, T. S., Mrs., 1928-1938 (Box-folder 8: 9)
  - Sobolevskii, T. B., 1935-1936 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - Soederboem, Georg, 1940 (Box-folder 8: 11)
  - Sokol'nitskii, Vladimir, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 8: 12)
  - Sotiuch, A. (?), 1941 (Box-folder 8: 13)
  - Sovremennyia Zapiski (periodical), 1932 (Box-folder 8: 14)
  - Speshnev, A. A., 1926-1939 (Box-folder 8: 15)
  - Stepanov, I. P., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 8: 16)
  - The Stratford Company, 1934 (Box-folder 8: 17)
  - Subetz, Vladimir A., 1933-1945 (Box-folder 8: 18)
  - Sumarokov, E., 1943-1945 (Box-folder 8: 19)
  - Telberg, G. G., 1939 (Box-folder 8: 20)
  - Tientsin Land Investment Co., 1935-1936 (Box-folder 8: 21)
  - Tientsin Women's Club, 1929 (Box-folder 8: 22)
  - Tobokov, Daniel M., 1937-1940 (Box-folder 8: 23)
  - Tolovachev, I., undated (Box-folder 8: 24)
  - Tolstoutov, I. F., 1924 (Box-folder 8: 25)
  - Tovarishchestvo "Russko-Man'chzhurskaia Knigotorgovlia" (Russian-Manchurian Book Trade Co.), 1929-1933 (Box-folder 8: 26)
  - Trankovsky, Tanya T., Mrs., 1946 (Box-folder 8: 27)
  - Varneck, E., 1930 (Box-folder 8: 28)
  - Vasiliev-Dubrovsky, Alexander N., 1931-1932 (Box-folder 8: 29)
  - Vasily, Father, 1927-1935 (Box-folder 8: 30)
  - Vestnik Kitaia (periodical), 1936 (Box-folder 8: 31)
  - Vetch, Henry, 1935-1938 (Box-folder 8: 32)
  - Victor, Archbishop, 1925-1944 (Box-folder 8: 33)
  - Volkoff, Boris, 1922-1933 (Box-folder 8: 34)
  - Vologodsky, Peter V., 1924 (Box-folder 8: 35)
  - Vologodsky, Zina, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 8: 36)
  - Vozrozhdenie (periodical), 1933 (Box-folder 8: 37)
  - Vyslanectvi Republiky Ceskoslovenske v Cine (Legation of the Czechoslovak Republic), 1935-1937 (Box-folder 8: 38)
  - W. M. Blackwood & Sons, Ltd., 1934 (Box-folder 8: 39)
  - Wrangel, M. D., Baroness, 1931 (Box-folder 8: 40)
  - Yale University Press, 1936 (Box-folder 8: 41)
  - Yartsov, Georgii, 1938 (Box-folder 8: 42)
  - Zabrovskii, F., 1923-1941 (Box-folder 8: 43)
  - Zaitseff, M. V., 1935-1936 (Box-folder 8: 44)
  - Zaria (periodical), 1942 (Box-folder 8: 45)
  - Zlokhorov, Tanya (Mrs. V. Leslie), 1928-1941 (Box-folder 8: 46)
  - Zverev, O. L., and I. F., 1922-1941 (Box-folder 8: 47)
  - Zvonnikov, A., 1941-1945 (Box-folder 8: 48)
- Writings, 1921-1968 (Boxes 9-17A)
  Writings by Alexandra N. and Ivan I. Serebrennikov, including typewritten and handwritten drafts, typewritten carbon and mimeographed copies, and printed copies of poems, articles, plays, and books, arranged alphabetically by title; newspaper clippings or articles; notebooks containing handwritten drafts of articles and poems, arranged chronologically; and translations, arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Drafts and printed copies of articles, books, plays, and poems, 1926-1945
    - Untitled, undated (Box-folder 9: 1)
    - "Aborigeny Iuzhnovo Kitaia" (Aborigenes of Southern China), 1929 (Box-folder 9: 2)
      Typewritten mimeographed copy
    - "Albazin i Albazintsy" (Albazin and Albazinians), 1935 (Box-folder 9: 3)
      Typewritten draft
    - "Al'truist Moti" (The Altruist Mo-Ti), 1941 (Box-folder 9: 4)
      Typewritten carbon copy
    - "Apostol Foma v Indii" (The Apostle Thomas in India), 1943 (Box-folder 9: 5)
    - "Asoka i Kanishka" (Asoka and Kanishka), 1942 (Box-folder 9: 6)
    - "Avtobiografiia" (Autobiography), 1933 (Box-folder 9: 7)
      Typewritten draft, two typewritten carbon copies
    - "Aziia--Kolybel' Pervichnoi Kul'tury" (Asia--Cradle of the First Civilization), undated (Box-folder 9: 8)
    - "Barga,", undated (Box-folder 9: 9)
      Typewritten draft, including English translation
    - "Bielovod'ie,", 1944 (Box-folder 9: 10)
      Typewritten mimeographed copy.
    - "'Biesy' Dostoevskavo" (Dostoevsky's The Possessed), undated (Box-folder 9: 11)
      Handwritten draft
    - "Bluzhdaiushchaiie Dushi" (Wandering Spirits), 1931 (Box-folder 9: 12)
    - "Chetyrnadtsataia Nalozhnitsa" (The Fourteenth Concubine), 1933 (Box-folder 9: 13)
      Typewritten draft, typewritten mimeographed copy
    - "Communism in China,", undated (Box-folder 9: 14)
    - "Den' Russkoi Kul'tury v Budushchem Rossiiskom Gosudarstvie" (Russian Culture Day in the Russia Yet to Come), undated (Box-folder 9: 15)
    - "Dieti i Dietskoe Slovotvorchestvo" (Children and the Creation of Words by Children), 1938 (Box-folder 9: 16)
    - "Dostoevskii v Sibiri" (Dostoevsky in Siberia), 1938 (Box-folder 9: 17)
    - "Drakon" (The Dragon), 1942 (Box-folder 9: 18)
      Typewritten mimeographed copy, includes English translation
    - "Dvie Lunnyia Nochi" (Two Moonlit Nights), 1942 (Box-folder 9: 19)
      Typewritten mimeographed copy, three printed copies
    - "Dvukhsotilietie Russkoi Poezii" (Two Hundred Years of Russian Poetry), 1939 (Box-folder 9: 20)
    - "Eastern Siberia,", undated (Box-folder 9: 21)
    - "Ekonomicheskoe Polozhenie S.S.S.R." (The Economic Situation in the U.S.S.R.), 1929 (Box-folder 9: 22)
    - "Epigrammy, Shutki i Parodii" (Epigrams, Jokes and Parodies), undated (Box-folder 9: 23)
      Typewritten carbon copy, printed copy
    - "'Evreiskii Mir'" (The World of the Jews), undated (Box-folder 9: 24)
    - "Evropeizatsiia Azii" (The Europeanization of Asia), 1928 (Box-folder 9: 25)
    - "Gosudarstvo Vei" (The Nation of Wei), 1942 (Box-folder 9: 26)
    - "A Great Retreat: Wanderings and Scatterings of the Russian White Armies in Northern and Central Asia,", undated (Box-folder 9: 27)
      Typewritten carbon copy, includes Russian translation
    - "The Historical Trend of Russian Policy in and Towards Outer Mongolia and Manchuria Including Eastern Inner Mongolia,", undated (Box-folder 9: 28)
    - "A Hun-Nu's Head,", 1943 (Box-folder 9: 29)
    - "Hunting Trophies in the Wilderness of Manchuria,", undated (Box-folder 9: 30)
    - "Irkutskaia Gruppa Oblastnikov" (The Irkutsk Regionalist Group), 1932 (Box-folder 9: 31)
    - "Ivan Maiskii,", undated (Box-folder 9: 32)
    - "Iz Besied Konfutsiia s Laotsy" (From Confucius Conversations with Lao-Tse), 1943 (Box-folder 9: 33)
    - "Iz Dalekavo Proshlavo" (From the Distant Past), 1945 (Box-folder 9: 34)
    - "Iz Proshlavo Sibiri" (From Siberia's Past), undated (Box-folder 9: 35)
    - "Iz Skazok Azii" (From the Folk-Tales of Asia), 1935 (Box-folder 9: 36)
      Handwritten drafts, typewritten mimeographed and carbon copies, includes English translation
    - "Iz Tian'tszinskoi Stariny" (From an Old Man of Tientsin), 1939 (Box-folder 9: 37)
    - "Iz Tibetskikh Skazanii" (From Tibetan Legends), 1939 (Box-folder 9: 38)
      Typewritten carbon copy, two printed copies
    - "Khoboiskoe Navodnenie" (The Ho-Bei Flood), undated (Box-folder 9: 39)
    - "Khudozhestvennyi Al'bom 'Vostochnavo Obozrieniia'" ( Eastern Review's Artistic Album), undated (Box-folder 9: 40)
    - "K Istorii Azii, Tom 2" (On Asian History, vol. 2), 1941 (Box-folder 9: 41)
      Typewritten drafts, typewritten carbon and mimeographed copies, printed copies
    - "K Istorii Izucheniia Sievero-Vostoka Azii" (On the Historiography of Northeast Asia), 1943 (Box-folder 9: 42)
      Typewritten mimeographed copy, printed copy
    - "K Istorii Russkavo Natsional'navo Gimna" (On the History of the Russian National Anthem), undated (Box-folder 9: 43)
    - "K Istorii Sibirskavo Pravitel'stva" (On the History of the Siberian Government), 1928 (Box-folder 9: 44)
    - "Kitai i Araby" (China and the Arabs), 1941 (Box-folder 9: 45)
    - "Kitaiskaia Meditsina" (Chinese Medicine), 1939 (Box-folder 9: 46)
    - "Kitaiskie Dominiony" (The Chinese Dominions), undated (Box-folder 9: 47)
    - "Kitaiskie Narodnye Verovaniia, Pover'ia i Nekotorye Obychai" (Chinese Popular Beliefs, Superstitions, and Several Customs), 1928 (Box-folder 9: 48)
      Handwritten draft, typewritten mimeographed copy
    - "Kitaiskie Shakhmaty" (Chinese Checkers), 1939 (Box-folder 9: 49)
    - "Kitaiskiia Izobrietenniia" (Chinese Inventions), undated (Box-folder 10: 1)
    - "Kitaiskii Narodnyi Panteon" (The Chinese Popular Pantheon), undated (Box-folder 10: 2)
    - "Kitaiskii Novyi God" (Chinese New Year), 1940 (Box-folder 10: 3)
    - "Kniaz' Gantimur" (Prince Gantimur), 1940 (Box-folder 10: 4)
    - "Kniaz'ia Gantimurovy" (The Princes Gantimur), 1938 (Box-folder 10: 5)
    - "Kniga o Tekushchikh Sobytiiakh" (A Book About Current Events), undated (Box-folder 10: 6)
    - "Konfutsii i Dzelu--Poema" (Confucius and Tsze-Lu--A Poem), 1936 (Box-folder 10: 7)
    - "Krasnyia Piki" (Red Spades), 1931 (Box-folder 10: 8)
    - "K Voprosu o Biudzhetnykh Issledovaniiakh v Kitae" (On the Question of Budgetary Studies in China), 1929 (Box-folder 10: 9)
    - "K Voprosu o Shamanizme v Kitae" (On the Question of Shamanism in China), 1933 (Box-folder 10: 10)
      Two typewritten carbon copies
    - "L. G. Kornilov,", 1943 (Box-folder 10: 11)
    - "Liudskaia Sila, Kak Sredstvo Trasporta v Kitae"(Manpower as a Means of Transportation in China), undated (Box-folder 10: 12)
    - "Liudskie Opustosheniia v Kitae" (Human Destruction in China), undated (Box-folder 10: 13)
    - "Liudskie Reservy Azii" (Asia's Human Reserves), 1928 (Box-folder 10: 14)
    - "Malen'kii Fel'eton" (A Short Satirical Article), undated (Box-folder 10: 15)
      Typewritten drafts, typewritten carbon copies
    - "Menandr i Nagasena" (Meandr and Nagsena), undated (Box-folder 10: 16)
      Typescript
    - "Mestnye Kul'ty" (Local Cults), undated (Box-folder 10: 17)
      Handwritten drafts
    - Moi Vospominaniia (Memoirs)
      - 1882-1901 (Box-folder 10: 18)
        Handwritten draft, 1938
      - 1901-1916 (Box-folder 10: 19)
        Handwritten draft, typewritten draft, 1933
      - 1917-1922 (Box-folder 10: 20)
        Typewritten mimeographed copy, 1937
      - 1925-1936 (Box-folder 10: 21)
        Handwritten draft, 1945
    - "Moi Vstrechi s Atamanom A. I. Dutovym" (My Encounters with Ataman A. I. Dutov), 1941 (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - "Nado Znat' Istoriiu Rodnoi Zemli" (You Should Know the History of the Motherland), undated (Box-folder 11: 2)
    - "Nakazannaia Zhadnost'" (Greed Punished), 1941 (Box-folder 11: 3)
    - "Na Polie Bitvy" (On the Field of Battle), 1930 (Box-folder 11: 4)
      Two typewritten mimeographed copies
    - "Na Tsyganskoi Svad'bie" (At a Gypsy Wedding), 1942 (Box-folder 11: 5)
      Typewritten mimeographed copy, two printed copies
    - "Nestoriane v Azii" (Nestorians in Asia), undated (Box-folder 11: 6)
    - "Novaia Kniga" (A New Book), 1938 (Box-folder 11: 7)
    - "Oboroten'" (The Werewolf), 1938 (Box-folder 11: 8)
    - "Obraztsy Kitaiskavo Fol'klora" (Samples of Chinese Folklore), undated (Box-folder 11: 9)
    - "O Budushchem Sibirskavo Oblastnichestva" (The Future of Siberian Autonomy), 1932 (Box-folder 11: 10)